So, what changes after 60 in parents' health insurance? There are
many things
that change,
we will talk about that for parents' health insurance.
If you are looking for health insurance for your parents
or you have some
questions regarding your parents' health
insurance, then I am sure this
video is a guide which will help you
in finding answers to all your questions regarding your parents' health insurance.  So
here we will talk about
why one should take health insurance for parents?
Subcent.  Secondly, how is your parents' health
insurance different from your health insurance
?  How
should he be treated differently?  Thirdly, the
health insurance premium of the parents
suddenly jumps.  How to
prevent it?  How to prevent him
from jumping?  And last but not the least, what are the
top health insurance plans that you
can consider for parents.
[Music]
Quick reminder before we start the video:
If you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, please do so so that
you get the right information at the right
time.  Today we will talk about
an ultimate guide about parents health insurance.
So first of all,
why do parents need health insurance?  As we can
see, problems arise with Edge.
Meaning, as we age,
as our age increases,
medical conditions also increase.  The
probability and chances of hospitalization
also increase.  So that's why
parents' insurance is very important.  Many
times it happens that your parents are covered
by some corporate.  Let's say they were
working.  you were working.  You have
covered your parents with an insurance company.
But how long?  That is as long as
you are with the corporate or as long as they
are with the corporate or they have the old
plan.  Many times it also happens that the
parents have CGHS cover or government
cover.  So, along with the government cover, it
is very important for them to have their own insurance.  Because they have flexibility.  You will never have to
think about getting treatment.
He is not dependent on anyone
that I have to get treatment.  So is this
in the panel or not?  This approval will happen or
not.  Here, whether the bed is available or
not in this category.  So
he will not plan for treatment accordingly.
If they have individual independent
insurance, then they have the freedom to get
treatment as per their wish and in their own way.  So parents'
insurance is extreme.
Why is the second one important?  If your parents are
financially dependent on you.  So
if he gets hospitalized and there
is no insurance cover, then whatever are your other
goals, you have made your goals from them.  There is
education for the children,
marriages for the children, buying a house,
buying a car, that money will be spent on the treatment of the parents.
Then your financial
planning will get spoiled.  So, it
is important to insure yourself.
More important than that is insuring the parents.
Because there is a higher probability for them that a
claim will come.  So if any big
claim comes there, then a lot of your finances will be
shaken here and there and your financial
planning will get spoiled.  Now you cannot think of parents'
insurance and our insurance in the same
way.  It Is A Different
Strategy All Together.  We take policies for ourselves.
We
offer policies with holistic comprehensive cover.  We
generally do not have any pre-existing conditions at a young age.
So we take policies accordingly.
We want policies at Young Age
that have value added services.  Like there is a
gym membership, fitness lessons
, step tracker.  Meaning, the more steps
you work, the more discount you get.
Maternity coverage and OPD
coverage were done.  Lots of add ons.
We need a very different policy for parents.
Parents need to cover pre-existing
conditions from day one.  If you already have
any disease and it needs to be covered from the first day, then
you have to focus on that.  Are there
any treatments of the parents that you want to cover early?  There
are some specific exclusions which you want to cover quickly,
so you have to focus on that.  If you want to take
any special health checkup packages for parents so that they can get
health checkup done once a year, then you should
focus on those plans
where health checkup is available.
What is the challenge?
Premium on parents' policy.  The premium jumps a lot.
So what happens here?  When the
premium is not affordable in the actual years when it is needed.
We were running the policy for so many years.  Was driving.
But when the need actually arose to make a claim
, the premium was
no longer affordable.  So there are many such tools or
enablers launched by companies where
you can afford the premium.
Such as deductible.  Deductible is a
small amount that you pay which
reduces your premium by 25
to 40% also.  Meaning it can be reduced by 40-50%
if you choose deductible.
You had a premium of X amount going from Lets.  If
you choose the deductible, it gets reduced by 40%.
But with a condition that
if any claim comes then
you will have to pay that deductible amount in the first claim
that is annual aggregate deductible.
Detailed video on deductible
is also available on our channel.  You can refer and
give a small amount yourself.  In return, the
insurance company gives a good discount.  If
your claim is not received then you can
enjoy the discount.  If a claim comes, then
pay that small amount in the claim.
All claims above that will be made by the insurance company.
Another concept is copayment.  So
you can also choose co-payment if you
want to reduce your premium.
Copayment is a percentage sharing in every
claim.  For example, the deductible is applicable only in the first
claim.
That sharing will happen in every claim only once a year.
You took an 80-20 copayment from Lets.  80% will
not pay for insurance.  You will pay 20%.
In return, you do
not have to pay the full premium.  Some
discounted premium has to be paid.  But
you will have to pay 20% on every claim.  So
these are some strategies to reduce the
premium.  Many times it happens in your policy that
you have taken any room category so that
I can get treatment in any room, be it deluxe or suite.
But
if you convert your policy to single room.
Many policies have
this option.
This is called room type modification.  What will happen if you convert it to a single room
?  Your
premium will be reduced.  A
discount of Rs 8,000 to Rs 10,000 is also available on the premium.
If you bring her to a single room.  And single
room is a decent room.  This story of the room
started after Covid.  When the hospitals
said that they did not have beds available.
And before that, a single room was
considered a single room.  Otherwise there was a
capping on room rate that 1% of the sum
assured would be given. Where the policy was of Rs 3 lakh, Rs
3000 would have been very less.  Now
generally people do not take a policy of Rs 3 lakh.
Take policies of Rs 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh.
Single room is available there so it is a
decent room.  So go for that.
Downgrade it from any room to
single room.  This will further reduce your premiums.
And to reduce the premium, you should
look at your add-ons.  What add-
ons are available in the policy?  Many times there are add ons
which we do not need.  Now
many such policies are coming where
you can choose add ons or covers,
optional covers and riders as per your choice.  Don't
add any riders you don't want.  Do not add any additional cover you do not need.
Pay for only the basic coverage.  So that makes a
big difference to your premium.
I was reviewing someone's policy the other day.
Give 65 plus.  I guess.
Maternity cover in their policy, in their policy, that
means very old policies are running
since 10-15-15 years.  What is the need for that thing now
?  You are paying additional premium
for these things.  So migrate to a policy
which does not have these features.  So last
we made a comparison video
for senior citizen plans.  You can check that.  Let me
tell you the names of the plans here
and the link to the comparison video
is in the description box and I am giving it below.
You should check and do your due diligence and
buy a policy for parents.   You
can see these plans - Niva Re 2.0, HDFCO Optima Secure, ICIC LBD, Elevate, Aditya Birla Active One and Manipal Cigna Sir Plan. There are some
specific senior citizen plans for senior citizens,
you can also refer them like
Niva Bhupa Senior First, but since
IRDA has removed the maximum entry age
and that in many policies,
anyone can enter in every policy, there is
no maximum age restriction, so
these policies also become eligible
for all, if your age is 65, 70
, 75, 80.  You can enter into this policy
at any given age.  So this was all what I
wanted to highlight for
parents' health insurance that firstly, do
not undermine parents' health insurance.  That health insurance
is very important and you should take it quickly because what if
tomorrow some medical condition is
diagnosed then perhaps the insurance company will
not give you the policy.  So it's better to
buy early.  The rules that apply to us apply to
them as well.  By-
products that are relevant to them.  The
features that are relevant to them.  Senior
citizen products generally have underwriting relaxation for them.  There is
no loading, waiting periods are short.
You should look at those products.  And last but
not the least, if the premium starts pinching then
adopt strategies.
Modify the deductible, co-payment, room rent
and
remove unnecessary riders.  In this way, the
premium will also be affordable.  Plus, there will be
cover for your parents and you will
also be completely free from any tension.  You will be
absolutely secure.  So
follow these steps and get your parents and
sure today.  If you have any questions, reach out
in the comment section.  If you want to reach out to our team,
contact details are mentioned.  You
can reach out.  And before we go, a
quick reminder, if you have
n't subscribed to our channel yet, please do so.
So that you get the right infection at the right
time.  See you in the next video.   Till then
stay safe.  Take care.  Bye-bye.
Om